MUGABE: Our own people
have got to realise
that they are not a separate entity
from the rest of the people.
We are a free people. a free nation.
Don't you realise that the people of
Zimbabwe are a sovereign people?
- We don't have to intervene...
- (CAR HORN HONKING)
Watch Online Movies and Series for FREE
www.osdb.link/lm
(PEOPLE ON PAVEMENT CHATTERING)
(RIFLE COCKING)
MUGABE: We don't have to
invite the British.
And who are they. after all?
Our invaders and colonisers
of yesterday.
(CROWD CHEERING)
Prepare for exit.
MUGABE: We can never lose.
They are going to fear us...
(SPEAKING SHONA)
(RIFLEMAN REPEATING DIALOGUE)
(GUN FIRES)
(COMMANDER GIVING INSTRUCTIONS)
Fuck!
(GUNS FIRING)
(CAR TYRES SCREECHING)
(SPEAKING SHONA)
Go on. bastard. do it.
Job done. Mugabe's dead.
How can you be so sure?
(SIRENS WAILING)
NEWS ANCHOR: President Mugabe
was uninjured in the attack.
but one of his body doubles
is reported dead.
The suspected gunman. Felix Masuku.
was immediately arrested
and two of his accomplices shot dead.
The Zimbabwean Intelligence Service.
the CIO.
claims that they have evidence
the assassination attempt
was planned by the British government.
with the help of...
(SWITCHING OFF TV)
This is becoming a serious problem.
COLLINSON: Christ!
He's a British soldier?
Was.
Felix Masuku's parents were
killed in 1982 by Mugabe's troops
in the Matabeleland massacres.
He fled Zimbabwe.
was brought up by an aunt in Peckham.
Age of 18.
he joined the Royal Engineers.
before returning to Zimbabwe
six years ago.
And you're concerned this history
adds credence to Mugabe's claim
that Britain is
behind the assassination?
- (PHONE RINGING)
- In one. Could you hold. please?
We need you to resolve
this problem. Hugh.
Understood.
So you want me
to break him out of prison?
Correct.
Masuku is being held in the secure wing
of Chikurubi Prison in Harare.
No guns. no noise.
No footprints back here.
This is a fully deniable operation.
Layla will be
your contact on the ground.
She'll be based in South Africa
until required in Harare.
You'll be travelling in
on a business visa.
This is your identity. Your cover
will be as an illicit diamond dealer.
"John Dean"?
Any objections?
It couldn't be James?
COLLINSON: The operation codename
is Ugly Trade.
Chikurubi was originally built
as a British fortress.
so we can provide you with
early blueprints. schematics.
archive photos. whatever you
might need to plan the escape.
Be under no illusion. this prison is
Mugabe's most secure facility
and Masuku will be under close watch.
So. how long do I have
to spring Masuku?
His trial is set for
eight weeks from now.
Look. if we can't leave footprints.
why send a Brit?
My point entirely.
You have a problem with this. Layla?
If we had no hand in the assassination.
then why are we
so concerned about Masuku?
Isn't this just another case
of deny. deny. deny?
Mugabe will use this as a show trial
to destroy the credibility of the UK
across the entire continent.
And believe me. it's fragile.
Right now. Masuku represents
a threat to the Realm.
He cannot be allowed to stand trial.
There is one other thing. John.
If this goes wrong...
The last bullet's for me.
Well. let's hope
it doesn't come to that.
John. I thought you should know.
As'ad's body hasn't been recovered.
As'ad! John! They're leaving him!
So he might still be alive?
Well. it's a big desert.
He didn't tell you anything?
(SPEAKING ARABIC)
Such as?
Anything that might tell us
where he could have gone.
I don't speak Arabic.
Your passport in the name ofJohn Dean.
driving licence and. um. condoms.
Standard issue for Africa.
Serviced any other officers recently
or was I the one with
particularly low self-esteem?
Well. we all have a job to do.
Some are more arduous than others.
(LIFT BELL DINGS)
Don't get your cock shot off.
RECEPTIONIST: That's right. put the name
of the person you want to see.
I'm really sorry. love. I'm not going
to be able to come up this weekend.
I don't really care what
your excuse is this time.
You've never been around and I...
I don't know why I should
expect you to be around now.
Alex. grow up.
The world doesn't revolve around you.
Why can't you understand that?
- Alex?
- John. it's me.
(SIGHING)
- Listen. um...
- I'm sorry. It's just...
You know. she's 17 now. She's got to
start understanding what it is I do.
No. No. no. no. It's not that. Um...
Listen. there's something
I've got to tell you.
- (KNOCKING ON DOOR)
- Just hang on one second.
Two minutes.
Sorry. love.
What was it you wanted to say?
Nothing.
- Sure?
- Yeah. It can wait.
Okay.
I'll call you when I get back.
I've got to go. okay?
- Okay.
- Bye.
(PHONE BEEPS)
Why didn't you tell him?
(COMPUTER BEEPS)
Felix Masuku.
who is also know as Raymond Frayn.
Irish passport.
South African passport. US passport.
These are all SAS issue IDs. sir.
It gets better.
Not only did Masuku
serve in the regiment
between January 2001 and March 2004.
but since returning to Zimbabwe.
he's been
an intelligence source for Ml6.
And we're claiming Masuku
doesn't work for us?
This isn't just embarrassing. this...
this really stinks.
And?
You knew this. didn't you?
Have you told Porter?
Porter knows what he needs to know.
Haven't you got a flight
to catch. Lieutenant?
CAB DRIVER: This place is dangerous
for you. my friend. huh?
Make sure you behave here. otherwise
you will end up in Chikurubi prison.
If you end up here. my friend.
oh. brother.
you can kiss your mother goodbye.
you will never see her again.
Harry Curtis. Welcome to Joburg.
I like the open-air approach
to the Embassy. Very un-British.
(CHUCKLES) It's what made sense.
that we met off-site.
Hope you're not too knackered.
Most people are undone by the altitude.
I had nosebleeds for a whole month.
Well. maybe that just happens to
high flyers. Mr First Secretary.
Hardly.
I got everything you asked for.
All legit South African documents.
In the name of a real-life
SONOP inspector. Lisbet Dreyer.
Her brief is counter-narcotics
and smuggling.
May I ask what these are for?
I'm a curious sort. you see.
I hadn't noticed.
Thank you. Mr Curtis.
Right.
DEALER: No. normally people
try and short-change me.
In this world.
you don't trust anyone. my friend.
(CHUCKLES)
Well. like you said.
trust no one.
(GUNS FIRING)
- Hands up.
- Easy. Take it easy.
(PORTER GRUNTS)
Here. take him away.
(MOBILE RINGING)
- Hello?
- Mr Dean's been picked up as arranged.
- When do you intend to visit?
- Tomorrow.
So. he's on his own till you get there.
Will he be comfortable?
He will be if he keeps his head down
and stays out of trouble.
(PEOPLE CHANTING AND SINGING
IN DISTANCE)
(GUARD ORDERING IN SHONA)
(GRUNTING)
Here. I'm God.
(PRISONERS CHATTERING)
- Why are you here?
- I made some bad choices.
Didn't we all. I'm Anthony Silongo.
(BOTH MOANING)
(LOUD THUD)
(ANTHONY MOANING)
(ANTHONY CRYING)
(ANTHONY SCREAMING)
(MAN SCREAMING)
(GUARD SHOUTING IN SHONA)
(SPEAKING SHONA)
(GROANING)
(PORTER GROANING)
(PORTER GRUNTING)
I've got information.
Useful information.
About the assassin.
(GUN COCKING)
Lexie.
What information?
I know him. I know who he is.
He'll trust me. I'm British.
(IN SOUTH AFRICAN ACCENT) My name
is Elisabeth Dreyer. Elisabeth...
Elisabeth Dreyer.
You are a despicable man.
You are a despicable man
in an ugly trade.
Ugly... Ugly...
My name is Elisabeth Dreyer. Dreyer.
(INSECT BUZZING)
(DOOR OPENING)
(PORTER GRUNTING)
(KINGSTON SPEAKING SHONA)
(PORTER MUMBLING)
He doesn't trust you. Mr Dean.
And to be honest. I don't blame him.
(METALLIC CLANKING)
(CHUCKLES)
- You've wasted my time.
- No!
GUARD: Sit.
Thank you. gentlemen.
Please.
Wow. I didn't know
they allowed conjugal visits.
- MrJohn Dean.
- Who wants to know?
The South African government do.
We've been monitoring
your smuggling activities.
We believe it's time
you were brought to account.
So it was you who had me arrested?
As I will have you extradited
to South Africa to face charges.
- Do you have anything to say?
- Yeah. darling.
I was wondering if you could get me
an upgrade. suite. Jacuzzi...
Okay. Mr Dean. Don't get clever with me.
From where I'm standing. you are
a despicable man in an ugly trade.
Listen. sweetheart.
You don't know what ugly is.
I've seen how ugly it can be in here.
Obviously you've come
face to face with it.
Yeah. I have.
Are you saying
you've received brutal treatment?
No. love. I'm not saying that.
I'm saying everyone has been
extremely well treated.
Everyone.
Thank you for your assistance.
Colonel Tshuma.
Pleasure to cooperate
with a friendly agency.
We would appreciate it if Mr Dean
could be moved to a secure wing.
We consider him to be
a dangerous criminal.
and until we have custody of him.
we need to know he's safe.
Of course. And once again. a pleasure.
Thank you.
You never touch Masuku. Understand?
Yes. sir.
And if anyone else asks to speak
to Mr Dean. I want to know about it.
(MOBILE RINGING)
- Yes?
- What news of Porter?
He's met the target face-to-face.
Says he's unharmed.
Masuku's not been tortured?
No. His words were
"extremely well-treated".
Really? That may help explain something.
Why?
We intercepted a communication.
They're moving Masuku to
a remand cell under the courthouse.
- When?
- Noon. the day after tomorrow.
Shit! Have they brought
forward the trial?
Yes. by two months.
And if they're not torturing Masuku.
then they must have
all the evidence they need.
We have to accelerate our plans.
I can't just walk back in there.
Tomorrow. then.
Porter has to know. Layla.
COLLINSON: You've got 48 hours.
I need a copy of
an extradition document. now.
CURTIS: Uh. where are you?
You know I can't
tell you that. Mr Curtis.
Okay. Uh. I'll send you
non-specific documentation.
you fill in the blanks.
(DIALLING TONE)
(GUARD SPEAKING SHONA)
- Who are you?
- Friend.
Your cell?
(TYPING ON KEYBOARD)
(KEY TURNING IN LOCK)
(DOOR OPENING)
PORTER: I don't suppose
we're off to breakfast?
Welcome. Mr Dean.
I'm guessing this isn't
Queensberry rules.
You guess right.
Vincent!
(ALL CHEERING)
ALL: (CHANTING) Vincent! Vincent!
Bet on me. I'll give him
the upper hand in the first round
and then you can take
all the odds you can get.
What's in it for you?
Keep him away from that boy.
Okay. We need a handicap.
(CHANTING STOPS)
(ALL CHEERING)
Ding-ding!
ALL: (CHANTING) Vincent! Vincent!
(CROWD EXCLAIMING)
(PEOPLE CONTINUE CHANTING)
(CROWD CHEERING)
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
You're not doing so well. my friend.
Double the odds.
I've got the Englishman!
(ALL CHEERING)
ALL: (CHANTING) Vincent! Vincent!
Vincent! Vincent! Vincent! Vincent!
All right! All right. boys.
Ding-ding!
ALL: (CHANTING) Vincent! Vincent!
Vincent! Vincent!
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
Come on!
(MEN CHEERING)
(PRISONERS BOOING)
Again? So soon?
Consider me your number one stalker.
Mr Dean.
I've prepared your extradition papers.
Time is of the essence.
You need to go through
everything thoroughly.
If there is anything you wish to appeal.
you have until tomorrow. midday.
This is all very sudden.
Deadlines are changing constantly.
Everything you need is in this document.
I should warn you that if I don't
receive your confirmation signature.
you might remain here indefinitely.
Do you understand what I'm saying?
It's possible...
I can give you my confirmation signature
first thing tomorrow.
Thank you. Mr Dean.
That would be a relief.
You need to remember this case number.
It will help drive through
the paperwork.
Colonel. how fortunate. I have a...
copy of Mr Dean's
extradition application for you.
How efficient. Miss Dreyer.
Usually I'm sent this
by your Department ofJustice.
I was able to expedite things.
So I see.
PORTER: Land Rover.
Under angel.
Land Rover under angel.
(KEY TURNING IN LOCK)
KINGSTON: You asked to see me?
Organise another fight.
Set two men against me.
- No one will bet against you.
- Except you.
I'll take the first fight.
I'll throw the second.
We'll both do well.
- When?
- Tomorrow morning.
Same time.
First light.
(LOCKING DOOR)
(MOBILE RINGING)
Tshuma.
AUTOMATED VOICE: You have
urgent mail from Littlefox.
(NECK CRACKS)
You're coming with me.
Am I?
Trust me.
(CHUCKLES)
(PHONE RINGING)
Hello. Chikurubi.
(CLATTERING ON PHONE)
Keys.
(DIALLING TONE)
- Where the fuck is everyone?
- Cock fight.
(ALL CHATTERING)
PORTER: Good girl. Layla. Let's go.
There's been a breach.
I've been compromised.
Get out. Head for the RV.
What about Porter? He needs transport.
- I can still get there.
- Look after yourself.
Get out now. Lieutenant.
that's an order.
Let's go.
- Isn't this is a dead end?
- Yep. But it's our way out.
What?
(SPEAKING SHONA)
(MEN SHOUTING IN DISTANCE)
(ALARM RINGING)
Stop.
Go back.
Give me a hand.
One. two. three...
(BOTH GRUNTING)
Okay. go.
(GUARDS RUNNING AND SHOUTING OVERHEAD)
Go.
(ALARM CONTINUES RINGING)
You're in charge.
Where the fuck are we?
Old munition tunnels.
Left or right?
Oh. fuck.
Down.
(GUN FIRING)
(SHOUTING IN SHONA)
(ALARM SOUNDING)
Where's the fucking Land Rover?
I don't fucking believe it!
Go! Go!
Hurry up!
(ENGINE SPUTTERING. REVVING)
Yes!
Get in!
Go. go!
Radio.
Radio traffic confirms
there has been a breakout
from Chikurubi.
Local police have been ordered
to set up roadblocks.
Oh. size 10. Result.
Shit!
Do you think he saw us?
What are we doing?
Ditching this piece of shit.
Cut some brush. we need to hide the car.
So you want me to
break him out of prison.
Masuku has to disappear completely.
Understood?
Sir.
(GUN COCKS)
Of course.
Drop the knife.
I said drop it.
Before you do this.
you should know something.
I was set up.
The whole assassination was a trap.
- They were waiting for me.
- On your knees.
I don't make mistakes. Dean.
I'm ex-regiment. just like you. Yeah.
I was hired by British Intelligence
to kill Mugabe.
Someone betrayed me.
I said get on your knees!
They betrayed me!
They betrayed you. too.
Where was the Land Rover. Dean?
- No. where was it?
- Shut up!
It was supposed to be there. wasn't it?
Think. Dean. think!
Those weren't prison guards
outside the prison.
they were Elite Guards.
What. 10 seconds after the alarm
went off. they're outside?
Tshuma's men?
Dean. the same men who captured me?
Who do you trust?
Who the fuck do you trust?
My name's Porter.
Sorry. mate. I only packed for one.
Understandable.
So what's plan B?
(SPEAKING SHONA. INDISTINCT)
LAYLA: It was Colonel Tshuma.
I'm sure of it.
COLLINSON: What makes you so certain?
His Elite Guard were
all over the Land Rover.
- It makes sense.
- Why. is there something else
you're not sharing with me?
We intercepted Elite Guard
transmissions from Chikurubi.
They were at the prison
immediately after Porter's jailbreak.
Shit! I should have driven to
the prison. got him out myself.
Layla. it was operationally
the right choice.
- For Porter or for you?
- Listen.
PORTER: (ON RADIO) SHopper.
this is Lancer. Come in.
- It's Porter.
- Shopper. this is Lancer. Come in.
Lancer. this is Shopper.
Glad to hear your voice.
I was expecting transport.
Apologies. Papa ordered me home.
Uninvited guests.
Is the Ugly Trade complete?
Change of mission.
Repeat. change of mission.
Prepare exit for two.
Christ! He's bringing out Masuku?
Tell him he can't.
Papa says mission
must be completed. Over.
Negative. Passenger has vital intel.
Explain. Lancer.
Passenger claims his job
was a legitimate UK contract.
Do you understand
what I'm saying to you? Over.
(DIALLING TONE)
Understood.
How long till you reach rendezvous?
We fancy a little walk.
We'll be with you tomorrow evening.
I'll wait for you. Reconnect 1800?
Copy that. Over and out.
Right. We need to head
for this location.
It's an exit camp just over the border.
Layla will debrief you there.
Layla?
The same woman who was
supposed to leave the Land Rover. yeah?
Yep.
- Can you trust her?
- It's not her I'm worried about.
I'll call you back.
Masuku claims he was recruited
directly by the British government.
- And you believe him?
- Right now. sir.
I don't know what to believe.
A bullet in Mugabe's head
might be desirable for some.
But the order did not come
from this office.
Well. then. that leaves
only two options.
- Which are?
- Either Masuku's lying
or he's been set up to think
he was working for us.
Is your man aware
of consequences of his actions?
There is one other thing. John.
If this goes wrong...
The last bullet's for me.
Yes. sir. Fully.
(SPEAKING SHONA)
Danni. Get me a file on all
UK intelligence liaison
for Zimbabwe over the last five years.
- Is this about Masuku?
- Yeah. Someone's recruited him.
someone's handling him.
I need to find out who.
- Are we looking for a double agent?
- Yeah. check all bank records
unusual patterns of behaviour.
you know the drill.
- Yes. sir.
- (MOBILE RINGING)
Diane?
LEXIE: (SOBBING) Where's Dad?
I need to talk to my Dad.
- Lexie?
- I need to talk to my dad. where is he?
It's my mum!
What is it?
Nothing. Let's just stop for a minute.
There's some water in the side pouch.
Thanks.
MASUKU: Shit!
We've got trouble.
Bushman. On the ridge.
- And scouts with a radio.
- Yep.
- Tshuma's men?
- Mmm-hmm.
Okay. we need to move.
No. no. no. That man can tell
how far ahead we are
just by the dent in our footprints.
Hard ground. Keep low.
Lexie.
(SOBBING)
(PANTING)
Porter.
Let's stay on the tarmac. No footprints.
Okay.
(SPEAKING SHONA)
Stop.
(ENGINE WHIRRING IN THE DISTANCE)
This way.
(TYRES SCREECHING)
Remind me not to come your way
next time.
(GUNS FIRING)
It could be worse.
(HELICOPTER APPROACHING)
It just got worse.
(HELICOPTER WHIRRING)
Lancer. this is Shopper. Over.
(STATIC ON RADIO)
Lancer. this is Shopper. waiting
at home. Do you read me? Over.
(STATIC CONTINUES)
Here. Cinderella. have a look at this.
Not a hope.
You know.
that's twice in my professional career
I've chosen not to kill someone
and lived to regret it.
Was the first an Iraqi kid?
How did you know about that?
Part of the training.
- Mistakes to learn from.
- Yeah?
And what have you brought to the party
apart from being a pain in the arse?
I just swept.
COLLINSON: Layla.
have you heard from Porter?
LAYLA: Not so far. sir.
I'll keep trying.
Okay. Speak soon.
Sir. here's Ml6's record
of all intel liaisons to Zimbabwe.
This person caught my interest.
He's been careless.
Harry Curtis. our Embassy contact.
His apartment in Joburg is paid
for out of his Civil Service salary.
But we discovered three other
properties purchased by him
under one of his logged aliases.
Alan Shenley.
- Did you follow the money?
- It wasn't hard.
Shenley has bank accounts
all around the world.
Antigua. Caymans. Liechtenstein.
$5 million we've traced so far.
- Where's the money coming from?
- Here.
Holmann Trust and Investments?
It's a Swiss bank
used by Mugabe's ministers.
Get me a flight to Joburg. tonight.
Sir.
(SPEAKING MATABELE)
- They've got a phone.
- Mmm.
(EXHALES)
What do you think?
It's too risky. We move on.
(GIRL SCREAMING IN MATABELE)
(MAN YELLING IN MATABELE)
(GRUNTS) He's going to rape her.
We do this quietly.
I'll cover the house.
(GIRL SCREAMING)
(MAN SPEAKING MATABELE)
(SHOUTING)
(GUN FIRING)
(MEN SHOUTING)
MASUKU: Porter!
Josette.
(SPEAKING MATABELE)
Uh...
phone?
Shit.
Who were those men?
Why does it matter to you?
They're Tsotsis.
Bandits.
If they find the bodies.
it will be very bad for us.
(SIGHS)
You're gonna have to bury them.
Lord.
though they be sinners.
please find it in your heart
to forgive these men.
And grant them eternal rest
in your kingdom.
amen.
- What was that for?
- For finding killing so easy.
Here.
Look. I'm sorry if we scared you.
I'm sorry. too.
I owe you thanks for saving Josette.
But you must go now.
Come with us. You and the children.
It's not safe here.
- Are you mad?
- We can't leave.
- Why not?
- Because she just said they can't.
The Tsotsis have a camp
just across the river.
If we leave...
MASUKU: What?
These men...
They smuggle people into South Africa.
And they use our orphanage
as a place for refugees to meet.
They're promised papers. passports.
and they hand over money.
I don't know what happens to them
when they leave here.
Come with us.
When Sister Carmel and Sister Mary
refused to help these men.
they shot them.
And now they always take two children
as hostages
to make certain we cooperate.
My burden is to care for those I can.
And my burden is to get you.
and you alone. across the border.
not traipse over the hills
like some cockeyed Von Trapp family.
- Do you know what this place is?
- I don't care what this place is.
We've got the Elite Guard
hunting us down.
These kids are AIDS orphans.
All they've ever known
is loss and abuse.
And anyone who's ever cared for them
is dead.
Porter!
Look. it's only. what. three or four
klicks to the Tsotsi camp?
We could get there. rescue the kids.
be back before sunset.
- No.
- Head off under cover of night.
- be over the border before daybreak.
- No.
It'll take Tshuma at least that long
to pick up on our trail.
- No. This is not my problem.
- Oh. right. right. Just ignore it.
You know what? At least I know
why I fight. you prick. Do you?
I'm not leaving here without these kids.
What are you gonna do. huh? Shoot me?
You bastard.
I'll get the rest of your stuff.
You're not going anywhere.
I'll be faster on my own.
Protect the farm. get the kids packed.
If I'm not back before sunset.
leave without me.
(EXHALES)
(GUN COCKING)
I've seen a lot of killing. Mr Porter.
Most men seem to take pleasure in it.
But you.
you're like a machine.
I don't know which frightens me more.
These are for Masuku.
And this is for the children.
It's not much. but they should eat
as well as they can before we leave.
Are you a good man sent by God.
Mr Porter?
Or evil. not to be trusted?
(CHORAL HYMN PLAYING)
JOSETTE: Sister?
SISTER BERNADETTE: Yes.
JOSETTE: Don't you think we should
say a prayer for the army man?
Of course.
JOSETTE: Lord. please protect Mr Porter.
May the angels guide him
to where he's going.
And please help him to deliver
our brothers back to us.
- Amen.
My god.
The refugees.
(SPEAKING SHONA)
Collinson. Mr Curtis. Section 20.
Going somewhere?
This is unexpected. Uh...
Would you like something? Some tea?
- Something stronger. perhaps?
- No. thank you.
- You speak Shona?
- As do you.
Handy for dealing with the regime
in Zimbabwe?
Sometimes you have to talk to people
you find unpleasant. Mr Collinson.
How true.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
(GASPS)
My name's Porter.
Sister Bernadette sent me.
Come on. Up there.
(MAN SHOUTING)
Run!
Move! Move!
Get down. go!
What was it. Curtis? Gambling debts?
A penchant for houseboys?
How did Tshuma turn you?
(SCOFFS) You'll forgive me
if this is a fantasy I don't recognise.
You and Colonel Tshuma. Harare.
four weeks ago.
You seem like good friends.
I'm obliged to form relationships
with Zimbabwean officials.
- What is this supposed to prove?
- On its own. nothing. But with this...
We've now found over $6 million
paid into your several accounts.
And according to your own files.
you recruited Masuku
as a sleeper in 2006.
So when Tshuma suggested you use him
to stage a fake assassination attempt.
everything was already in place.
Relax. Curtis.
You're still of use to us.
I'm here to offer you
a chance of redemption.
All we ask is that you continue letting
Tshuma believe you're working for him.
but in reality
you'll be working for us.
Your money will. of course.
have to be impounded by the exchequer.
but think of it as a... a donation.
Forgive me.
COLLINSON: No!
Curtis. you fucker!
(RIFLES FIRING)
Get over the bridge
and don't stop running
until you find Sister Bernadette.
Do you understand? Go!
BOTH: Porter!
Porter!
Shit.
Don't move. Stay where you are.
It's all right. I've got you.
Go. run! Go. go. run! Go!
Go.
Ah. fuck!
(GRUNTING)
"Little Fox."
Sister Bernadette!
Where's Porter?
PORTER: (GRUNTING)
We need to staunch this.
- Shit. I'll get the first aid kit.
- Bring some cordite.
(GRUNTING)
Lie down.
(GROANING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
This is gonna hurt.
(SCREAMING)
(SISTER BERNADETTE GASPS)
(GROANS)
It's all here.
Times. dates. communications.
No wonder they didn't need
to torture Masuku.
But does it prove that
the assassination attempt was a set-up?
Not with Curtis dead.
All we have here
is a legitimate UK government official
planning a hit on Mugabe
using a former SAS operative.
We can deny all we like.
but the evidence looks overwhelming.
Our only hope is if Porter can
get Masuku across that border.
- Any news?
- No word.
Okay. Stand by your phone.
I'm going to have to clean this mess up.
(WIND CHIME TINKLING)
(GROANS)
Lie still or you'll open the wound.
- What time is it?
- Around noon.
Kids are packed. ready to go.
We need to get moving.
(GRUNTS)
Who's that?
Get down.
- Go to the children. keep them quiet.
- Okay.
PORTER: Pass me the FM.
Did you get him?
Bollocks.
That would have been useful.
Oh. well. excuse me all over the place.
They'd have radioed their last position.
- How long do you think we've got?
- Two hours. Three at best.
Right. we need to get moving.
(GRUNTS)
You need to head for this location.
it's about 12 kilometres from here
across the border.
You'll find a camp
and a woman called Layla.
Give her this note
and she'll look after you.
You're not coming with us?
No. No. if I do. I'll put you
and the children in greater danger.
Masuku will be with you.
I don't understand.
Tshuma's hunting us down. If I stay.
I might be able
to hold him off long enough
so that you can get
across the border to safety.
I've got the answer
to my question. Mr Porter.
May God protect you.
MASUKU: Sister.
I don't think I'll be going.
I'm going to stay here.
Sister. look after those kids. yeah?
Where do you think you're going?
You know as well as I do
their best chance is
if we both make a stand.
I really wish I'd shot you.
You believe the British
will let me live?
I thought I was paranoid.
Sure they'll want to hear
what I have to say. yeah. but then what?
- As long as I'm alive. I'm a liability.
- True.
I'm Matabele. John.
I was born a warrior.
My blood belongs here. in this red soil.
- Anyway. we have an advantage.
- What's that?
Tshuma needs us alive.
(CHUCKLES) Great.
Okay.
- So we've got the four AKs...
- Yeah.
...the FM...
- Mmm-hmm.
...the shotgun. the Tokarev
and three grenades.
Four. Where did you get those from?
Off the Tsotsis
you dropped by the river.
Didn't have an RPG on them. did they?
(LAUGHS)
Bloody hell. My dad had one of these.
No! So did mine.
(CHUCKLES)
Unbelievable. It's full.
Ironic. All we need now is four wheels
and we're out of here.
(HISSING)
Backed in a corner. mate.
I know how you feel.
(HISSING)
(COCKS GUN)
John Dean. if that really is your name.
Why don't you just give me Masuku?
Do that
and I'll consider letting you live.
I saw the grave you dug for him. Dean.
Are you really willing
to die for him now?
Or is that your weakness?
You have a conscience?
Yeah. I'm all heart.
(MACHINE GUNS FIRING)
(SPEAKING SHONA)
Oi! Looking for me?
Fuck!
(SHOUTING IN SHONA)
Time to go?
Bomb.
(SHOUTING IN SHONA)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(RIFLES FIRING)
- Crap.
- What?
They've got an RPG.
- I thought you said he wanted us alive.
- I can't be right all the time.
Go!
What is he playing at?
Fuck!
Clever bastard.
(SCREAMS)
You're actually enjoying this.
aren't you?
(SHOUTING IN SHONA)
Plan?
Take out as many as we can.
Save two rounds.
One for you. one for me.
I'd better not arrive in hell
and find out you're not there.
(ALL SHOUTING)
What the fuck is this?
(SHOUTING)
- Friends of yours?
- South Africans.
(GUNFIRE CONTINUES)
Cease fire! Cease firing!
You three. check the house.
John Porter. I presume.
Impressive woman.
that Sister Bernadette.
You'll be glad to know
she and the children
arrived safely at our exit camp.
- Layla was...
- Dean!
Dean.
Bastard.
It's Porter.
(GROANS)
(GROANING)
SOLDIER: We searched the house
but Masuku isn't there.
Where's Masuku?
Drowned.
River jump. Deep water.
- What happened to the body?
- No idea.
The current must have taken it.
- You okay?
- I'll live.
Good.
That's for leaving my arse on the road
outside the prison.
John? John!
We need to talk about Lexie.
It was meant to be
a really simple operation
to remove a tumour.
There was a... There was a complication.
I don't really understand what happened.
Oh. sweetheart.
Shh. Shh. baby.
I'm sorry. I'm...
Shh.
I'm just not as used to death
as you are.
I didn't mean that. I'm sorry.
Yeah. you did.
You're right.
You hang in there for me. yeah?
I'll be home soon.
I love you.
I love you. too.
(EXHALES)
(SOBBING)
She can stay with Jenny and me
as long as she needs.
She's my daughter.
Stop putting me in your debt.
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
Come in. Danni. I'm just...
Sorry to disturb you.
What's on your mind. Layla?
I need to know what happened
during the Bratton extraction in 2003.
Porter!
Where are the other men? Collinson!
Where's Mike and Keith?
- Fuck!
- They're dead! Porter!
Porter!
Why do you want to know?
Because I need to trust the people
my life depends on.
There's history between
you and Collinson. Secrets.
And at this point in time.
I don't trust either of you.
Tell me. John.
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today